Guide to the Words of the World's Children Collection, 1979-2015.
Words of the World's Children Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Words of the World's Children Collection, 1979-2015.
8525
Lust, Barbara,
88 cubic feet.
Sound and A/V recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes tapes and records concerning language development in children.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
This collection consists of audio and audio-visual recordings, and records of child language. It is cross-linguistic with assessments in each language which are comparable across languages.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes tapes and records concerning language development in children.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lust, Barbara, 1941,; New York State College of Human Ecology.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; Language acquisition.; Linguistics.; Children -- Language.; Language and languages -- Ability testing.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Experimental Data
  - Japanese (some Sinhala)
    - Japanese Correspondence, Papers; Experiment 1,2 study 3,4 (Box 1)
    - Japanese Study 6,7 (Box 2)
    - Japanese Paper Presentation Material; Studies 1,2,3,4 and Natural Speech (Box 3)
    - Japanese Papers/Drafts 1 (Box 4)
    - Japanese Study 3,4 (Box 4)
    - Japanese Study Experiment 1,2 (Box 5)
    - Japanese Paper/Drafts 2 (Box 5)
    - Japanese Study 6,7. Imitation Scoring Sheets; Sinhala Study 2 data/scoring sheets (Box 9)
    - Japanese Study 5. To-nagara Anaphora (Box 6)
    - Japanese Study 5 continued (Box 7)
  - Chinese
    - Chinese study- WYN Transcripts. (Box 7)
    - Chinese Sloppy Identity (Box 10)
    - Chinese Sloppy Identity/WYN Study (Box 10)
    - Chinese Natural Speech- Experiment Analyses and Packard R.C. Study (Box 11)
    - Chinese C-O study; B.R. study; W-B-A study (Box 11)
    - Chinese C-O study; B.R. study; W-B-A study continued (Box 12)
  - Hindi
    - Hindi Paperwork (Box 25)
    - Hindi Paperwork continued (Box 26)
    - Hindi Materials/Stats (Box 14)
    - Hindi Paperwork Box 1 (Box 15)
    - Hindi Act-Out (Box 16)
    - Hindi Act-Out Box Phase 2 (Box 17)
    - Hindi Project presentation materials (Box 18)
    - Hindi-Sinhalese Comparisons (coordination data) (Box 18)
  - Arabic
    - Arabic Study (Box 19)
      a. Arabic Study 1 and 2. 1 Audio Tape. Side 1. Hazin s. S #34, Side 2. Tariq a. S #20
      b. Scotch Magnetic Audio Tape: Arabic Nat. Speech Coord. For Reliability S # 33, S # 31, S #32 Related materials
      See also box 79.
    - Arabic Study I (Box 18)
    - Arabic Study I (Box 19)
    - Arabic Study I (Box 20)
  - Malayalam
    - Malayalam Audiotapes and paperwork (Box 21)
      a. 2 audiotapes: Aditya Manjo
      b. 1 Video(VHS): Aditya Manjo: Aug 15, Sept 16, Oct 3, Nov 6 2003 Session data
      c. 1 zip disk Malayalam subject screens 001-037 session screens
  - Inuktitut
    - Inuktitut Dissertation (Box 21)
    - Inuktitut Records (Box 22)
      David Parkinson Dissertation
  - Tulu
    - Tulu; Shamitha (Box 23)
  - Korean
    - Korean Imitation/TV Study; transcripts, scoring sheets (Box 23)
    - Korean Imitation/TV Study; transcripts, scoring sheets, oversized items (Box 24)
  - Spanish
    - Spanish Experimental Data-Zelmira Nunez del Prado study; prodrop (Box 26)
    - Basque/Spanish Experimental data. Transcripts and Backups (Box 27)
  - German
    - German Boser (Box 27)
    - German Boser (Box 28)
    - German L-I Acquisition Experiment Katerina Boser Data (Box 29)
  - English
    - English Experiment Sloppy Identity Data (Box 30)
    - English Experiment Sloppy Identity Data (Box 31)
    - Sloppy Identity Organization Expt. Papers (Box 31)
    - Sloppy Identity Organization Expt. Papers (Box 32)
    - English experiment (related to sloppy exp. #4) (Box 32)
    - English Sloppy Identity Pic Judgement, Box 1 (Box 33)
    - English Sloppy Identity Pic Judgement, Box 1 (Box 34)
    - English Sloppy Identity Pic Judgement, Box 2 (Box 34)
    - English Sloppy Identity Pic Judgement, Box 2 (Box 35)
    - English Mudpie experiment (Box 35)
    - 53. English Experiment GAPPING (Box 36)
    - Pro-0 English Study (Box 36)
    - Pro-0 English Study (Box 37)
    - Early studies; English and cross-linguistic; Extra Forms for complete studies (Box 37)
    - Early studies; English and cross-linguistic; Extra Forms for complete studies (Box 38)
    - English T. Clifford 3-D Pronoun Study (Box 39)
    - English experiment Data and Statistics. E.I. Pronoun Studies (Eisele and Goss) (Box 40)
    - English Coordination and Natural Speech Original Experiment and Data, oversized material (Box 24)
    - English Early Coordination Study (Box 41)
    - English 4D Ambiguity, Eisele et al Studies (Box 41)
    - English experiment (TVJT) Eisele (Box 41)
    - English experiment (TVJT) Eisele (Box 42)
    - English experiment V.P. Ellipsis study 1 (Box 42)
    - English experiment (TVJT) Eisele (Box 43)
    - English experiment, LLK (Box 44)
    - English E.I. experiment Inversion files (Box 45)
  - Experimental Data Additional Materials
    - Michelle Dixon Honors Thesis: Acquisition of Semantics/Quantifiers (2006)Data (Box 63)
    - ProDrop Experiment Data – Zelmira Nunez del Prado (Box 63)
- Natural Speech Files and Transcripts
  - Natural Speech Inventories-early forms (Box 45)
  - Natural Speech Inventories-early forms floppy disks (Box 13)
  - German Natural Speech (Box 46)
  - Korean Natural Speech transcripts (Box 46)
  - Korean Natural Speech transcripts (Box 47)
  - Arabic Natural Speech (Box 47)
  - Hindi Natural Speech (Box 47)
  - Hindi Natural Speech (Box 48)
  - Hindi Natural Speech (Box 49)
  - Chinese Natural Speech Original transcripts and experiment 1 (Box 50)
  - Chinese Natural Speech (Box 51)
    a. Audio Tapes: Original subject 1-1-1
    b. 5 floppy disks: Amy’s files
    See also box 81
  - English Natural Speech Study by Lust and Clifford on Pronouns (Box 52)
  - English Natural Speech Records (Box 52)
  - Master English Natural Speech A-L (Box 53)
  - Master English Natural Speech M-Y (Box 54)
- Literature
  - Articles put on Mann Reserve and Student Papers (Box 55)
  - Binding Theory Literature (Box 56)
  - Learnability Literature (Box 57)
  - Subset Principle Literature (Box 58)
  - Experimental Data: Paper presentation materials - GLOW 1987, 1990 (Box 59)
  - Papers on South Asian Linguistics (Box 59)
  - Papers on South Asian Linguistics (Box 60)
  - Papers on Hindi, Bengali, Maratai, Tamil, Sinhalese, Teluga, Kannada (Box 60)
  - Chinese Literature (Box 60)
  - Chinese Literature (Box 61)
  - References on Japanese Literature (Box 61)
  - References on Japanese Literature (Box 62)
  - Korean Acquisition / Linguistics Literature (Box 62)
  - Chinese Literature (Box 62)
  - IP-DP Literature (Box 64)
  - IP-DP Literature (Box 65)
  - Javanese Transcripts (Box 65)
    See box 83 for tapes.
- Media
  - English Tapes
    - CLAL: Eng-0001 - 0150 AC 1971-1978 (Box 66)
      1-65 NS and El (E tapes)
      66--144 CE Copies
      145-150 Org. Coor. '73-'75
    - CLAL: Eng-0151 - 0295 AC (Box 67)
      151-157 Org. Coor. '73-'75
      158-195 Coor. Because '76-'78
      196-241 Pronoun Study '78-'79
      242-295 Relative Clause '79
      Missing 245
    - CLAL: Eng-0296 - 0441 AC (Box 68)
      296-309 Relative Clause '79
      310-344 3D '79-'80
      345-408 Coor. Gapping '79-'80
      409-441 Null-Pro '80
      Missing 297 and 353
    - CLAL: Eng-0442 - 0585 AC (Box 69)
      442-489 Null-Pro '80
      490 Summer '82
      491-524 3D Pronoun '83-'84
      525-577 EI & Act Out Pronoun '86-'87
      578-585 TVJT, 4DBF, Ambiguity '87-'90
    - CLAL: Eng-0586 - 0734 AC (Box 70)
      586-650 TVJT, 4DBF, Ambiguity '87-'90
      651-656 NS and EI (E tapes continued) '88
      657-661 Mudpie '89
      662 '90 GIAC
      663-673 Prodrop & Pic judge '91-'93
      674-698 Sloppy ID '92-'98
      699-705 NS '93
      703-734 Inversion '94-'96
      Missing 730
    - CLAL: Eng-0735 - 0846 AC (Box 71)
      735-758 Inversion '94-'96
      759-792 Inv. Copies '94-'96
      793-797 Brian Gair NS '98-'99
      798 Moskowitz '00
      799-846 VP ellipsis file and Sloppy ID II
      Missing 781, 786-788
    - Second Language Acquisition Gita-SLA (Box 81)
      3 Audio tapes
      a. Audio Tape: Replacement Test-Abby
      b. Audio Tape: UG Test #1
      c. Audio Tape: UG Test #2
      d. Related materials
      May be in Box 80
  - Sinhala Tapes
    - Sinhala Experiment #1 1981 Natural Speech (Box 72)
      Tapes 001-071
    - Sinhala Experiment #1 1981 Natural Speech Backups (Box 87)
    - Sinhala Experiment #2 1983 Imitation and Act-Out (Box 72)
      Tapes 072-144
    - Sinhala Experiment #2 1983 Imitation and Act-Out Backups (Box 87)
    - Sinhala Experiment #3 1985 Imitation and Act-Out (Box 73)
      Tapes 145-242
    - Sinhala Experiment #3 1985 Imitation and Act-Out Backups (Box 88)
    - Sinhala Experiment #4 1984-1985 Imitation and Natural Speech (Box 73)
      Tapes 232-271
    - Sinhala Experiment #4 1984-1985 Imitation and Natural Speech Backups (Box 88)
  - French Tapes
    - French Tapes - Foley (Box 73)
      14 tapes. Missing 7, 11, 13, 14
    - French: Dye corpus, CDs (Box 86)
  - Tulu Tapes
    - Tulu Tapes: H-tapes (Box 74)
      1-12. Some missing.
    - Malayalam Tapes (Box 74)
      1-22
    - Tulu Tapes 1-83 and V. H. Tapes - 19 (Box 74)
  - Hindi Tapes
    - Hindi - Bhopal Tapes 1-37 (Box 75)
    - Hindi - Hyderabad Tapes 1-96 (Box 75)
    - Hindi - Pakistan Tapes 1-8 (Box 75)
    - Hindi - AGRA Tapes Natural Speech (Box 75)
    - Hindi - Delhi Natural Speech and Imitation (Box 75)
    - Other Hindi Tapes (Box 79)
    - Hindi back up tapes (Box 89)
  - Spanish Tapes
    - Maria Spanish Tapes (Box 76)
    - Spanish Data Tapes (video) Blume, Maria (Box 89)
  - Mother - Infant Study - Theresa Fives
    - CDs, Subject No.1-11 and copies (Box 89)
    - Motherese corpus, CDs (Box 89)
  - Natural Speech Tapes
    - Chinese study- WYN Imitation Audio Tapes/Sloppy Identity Act-Out (Box 8)
      Videos (VHS): Groups 1-9 VHS Tapes 1-21
      Analogue Audio Tapes: Box’s 3-9 Audio Tapes #’s 0309-2113
    - Chinese and Japanese Analogue Audio Tapes (Box 83)
      Japanese Study 8 Audio Tapes
      BR Audio Tapes 1-1 - 1-25, missing 9, 11, 18
      BR Audio Tapes 2-1 - 2-22, missing 16
      BR Audio Tapes 3-1 - 3-25, missing 5, 15-17
      BR Audio Tapes 4-1 - 4-22, missing 4, 13
      BR Audio Tapes 5-1 - 5-26, missing 11, 19
      May be in box 77.
    - Chinese and Japanese Analogue Audio Tapes (Box 78)
      WBA Audio tapes, 0-1, 1-24, 2-25, 3-22, 4-21, 5-6, some tapes missing
    - (=T 59) Hindi Audio Tapes-Phase 2 (Box 78)
      a. Phase 2 Pilot Data Audio Tape
      b. Actout/Imitation Phase 2 Audio Tapes, Groups 2-9 (each in own box)
      i. Group 2 N = 22
      ii. Group 3 N = 5
      iii. Group 4 N = 17
      iv. Group 5 N = 22
      v. Group 6 N = 22
      vi. Group 7 N = 13
      vii. Group 8 N = 25
      viii. Group 9 N = 7
      c. Also contain 2 audio tapes (no labels)
    - Arabic Study (Box 79)
      See also box 19
    - Arabic Study (Box 84)
    - German - Boser studies (Box 80)
    - Korean Natural Speech - audio tapes (Box 80)
    - Chinese - natural speech audio tapes (Box 81)
      See also box 51
    - Japanese Natural Speech - audio tapes (Box 82)
      Some tapes missing.
    - Japanese Studies 3, 4, audio tapes (Box 83)
    - Javanese Tapes (Box 83)
      See transcripts in box 65
    - English - Sloppy Identity Experiment, audio Pix Judgement task 1-12 (Box 83)
    - Japanese Study 5, audio tapes, imitation and act out data (Box 84)
    - Japanese and Korean Audio Tapes (Box 84)
    - Inuktitut - audio tapes (Box 85)
      Includes spreadsheet
    - Lectures of courses (BL) audio tapes (Box 86)
    - Inuktitut - videos (Box 90)
    - Japanese Study 5, video tapes, imitation and act out data (Box 90)
    - English - Sloppy Identity Experiment Videos / act out data 1-37 (Box 90)
  - Dutch Tapes
    - Study by Isabelle Barbier, conducted in Belgium (78 tapes) (Box 91)
- Left in Storage Locker not Boxed
  - Original Statistical Data Outputs (Box 168)
    Stats Outputs/cross-linguistic and early experiments.
    3 drawer file cabinet
- Items not in storage locker or box numbers other wise not matched
  These are items that were not included in the original transfer, perhaps still in Barbara's lab. They include their original box number as assigned by Barbara not the RMC box number.
  - Chinese and Japanese Files –[MOVED TO BL’S OFFICE] (Box 17)
  - Sinhala
    - Sinhala experiment 1,2,3,4 subject sheets (Box 18)
    - Sinhala Imitation I and II records (Box 19)
    - Sinhala Experiments II and III. (Box 20)
    - Sinhala experiment II scoring sheets (Box 21)
    - Sinhala Experiment Data #4 (Box 22)
      Contains 6 Audio Tapes
    - Sinhala Study 4 scoring sheets –deleted; combined with 22. (Box 23)
  - Korean Acquisition General information/memo conference Box 1 (Box 39)
  - Korean Acquisition General information/ memo conference Box 2 (Box 40)
  - English experiment Relative Clause data – [IN LAB, MVR G17] (Box 65)
  - Experimental Data Box 1 (Box 69)
  - Experimental Data Box 2 (Box 70)
  - Experimental Data Box 3 (Box 71)
  - Sinhala Natural Speech transcripts Box 1 (Box 79)
  - Sinhala Natural Speech transcripts Box 2 (Box 80)
  - Inuktitut Research Materials (Box 157)
  - Piaget Lab Course Materials
    Used for Piagetian Tasks, including those on video tapes
    - Piaget Lab Course Materials (Box 158)
    - Piaget Lab Course Materials (Box 159)
    - Piaget Lab Course Materials (Box 160)
    - Piaget Lab Course Materials (Box 161)
    - Piaget Lab Course Materials (Box 169)
  - Literature on Second Language, L2, Acquisition (Box 163)
  - Literature on Second Language, L2, Acquisition (Box 164)
  - Literature on Second Language, L2, Acquisition (Box 165)
  - Literature on Second Language, L2, Acquisition (Box 166)
  - References: Endnotes project (Box 167)
    References to be checked against Endnotes database